New Zealand has announced a world first
scheme that would see a tax introduced
on emissions from burping farm animals
the move is part of the country's plan
to tackle climate change but it has
already faced backlash from Farmers
nice to meet you an emissions tax to
reduce greenhouse gases were better out
than in will soon be costing Farmers New
Zealand's prime minister has unveiled a
world-first strategy to tax emissions
from burps and urination produced by
farm animals key to us that what we do
is workable that it's pragmatic that it
can be introduced in a timely way and
that it will actually bring down our
emissions as farmers and as food
producers show the world how we can
reduce our carbon footprint and feed the
world in the way that they expect in New
Zealand dairy products are the nation's
largest export earner emissions are
sizable with twice as many cattle and
five times the number of sheep to people
meaning more than half of the country's
greenhouse gases comes from farms in New
Zealand methane emissions count for 97
of total agricultural emissions in
Australia agriculture contributes around
13 of our greenhouse gas emissions each
year to measure emissions animals are
placed in animal-friendly respiration
Chambers gas output is measured over two
days through automated systems sampling
air entering and leaving the chamber
temperature food air and humidity are
all controlled to produce the most
accurate result possible
an agricultural calculator from the
ministry for the environment shows for a
farm with 40 cattle 73 tons of emissions
are released per year an average dairy
farm has around 10 times that of a herd
of around 440 cows that's 1 307 tons of
emissions per year
consultation document does and some of
the modeling has drawn out that for a
dry stock in particular just because of
the emissions profile in the living
system we do see a greater impact this
we are specifically saying to that part
of our primary sector we want to work
together New Zealand has pledged to go
carbon neutral by 2050. the intention is
to reduce methane emissions by 10 by
2030 and up to 47 by 2050 under the
proposed plan payments for emissions
would begin in 2025 with the amount yet
to be finalized for some Farmers the
news was hard to digest a lot of farmers
that are contacting me are feeling
pretty uh say pretty upset would be a
mild understatement
um they're you know it's kind of feeling
very ropable the message I'm getting
from Farmers is we must oppose this The
Proposal will provide Financial
incentives for Farmers to reduce
emissions the Money Paid will also be
reinvested in the sector I was proposing
a more
of the up and running by 2025 and also
it didn't have the support of the sector
consultation on the proposal will be
open until November 18. Jessica Maggio
Sky News